Guide to the Indivisible: Stories of American Community photographs and project records, 1988-2002 and undated
Indivisible: Stories of American Community photographs and project records 1988-2002 and undated
- Photographs Series, 1999-2002, (20 boxes)
  - Lynn Davis (United States, b. 1944)
    - USS Northwestern (bombed in WWII), Dutch Harbor, Aleutians, 1999, (L2000:008:006) (Box 37)
    - Russian Orthodox Cathedral of the Holy Ascension, built 1826, rebuilt 1853-1858, existing church 1890-, Unalaska, Aleutians, 1999, (L2000:008:007) (Box 37)
    - Halibut, Sitka, Alaska, 1999, (L2000:008:009) (Box 37)
    - Nets, Sitka, Alaska, 1999, (L2000:008:011) (Box 37)
      Not in in book or traveling exhibition.
    - Theo Grutter, Sitka, 1999, (L2000:008:012) (Box 37)
    - House of a Subsistence Fisherman, Kogwonton Street, Sitka, 1999, (L2000:008:013) (Box 37)
    - Tramp Steamer, Unalaska, Aleutians, 1999, (L2000:008:014) (Box 37)
    - Large Marge's Dog, World War II Bunker, Dutch Harbor, Aleutians, 1999, (L2000:008:015) (Box 37)
    - Joe Shaishnifkoff, Dutch Harbor, Aleutians, 1999, (L2000:008:016) (Box 37)
    - Theo Grutter's Son, Ivan, Sitka, 1999, (L2000:008:017) (Box 37)
    - Seafood Processing Plant Worker, Sitka, 1999, (L2000:008:018) (Box 37)
    - Halibut, Sitka, 1999, (L2000:008:019) (Box 37)
    - World War II Bunker, Dutch Harbor, Aleutians, 1999, (L2000:008:020) (Box 37)
      Not in book. Variant image in traveling exhibition.
  - Terry Evans (United States, b. 1944)
    Nineteen 16x20, 20x24, and 24x24" chromogenic prints of Yaak Valley, Montana landscapes, and loggers and other individuals, documenting change and social and environmental concerns in their communities.
    - Oyster and Clam Benefit for the School Given by Yaak River Tavern, Yaak, Montana, June 1999, (L2000:023:002) (Box 31)
    - Mary, Ken, and Chiena Burggraf, Yaak, Montana, June 1999, (L2000:023:004) (Box 31)
    - Crash Karuzas, logger, Yaak, Montana, June 1999, (L2000:023:014) (Box 31)
    - Jesse Sedler, Yaak, Montana, June 1999, (L2000:023:015) (Box 31)
    - Jesse Sedler, horse logger, Yaak, Montana, June 1999, (L2000:023:016) (Box 31)
    - Pete Creek Road, Yaak Valley, Montana, June 1999, (L2000:023:005) (Box 32)
    - Haakon, Aaron and Shirley Karuzas, Yaak, Montana, June 21, 1999, (L2000:023:006) (Box 32)
    - Jesse Sedler and Strider, Yaak, Montana, June 1999, (L2000:023:007) (Box 32)
    - Linda Stehlik's Cabin, Yaak, Montana, February 1999, (L2000:023:008) (Box 32)
    - Reuben Kneller at his sawmill, Yaak, Montana, June 1999, (L2000:023:009) (Box 32)
    - Zeita Mae Romeiko, Yaak, Montana, June 1999, (L2000:023:010) (Box 32)
    - Camille, Cherith, Cassia, and Cedar Leidigh, Yaak, Montana, June 1999, (L2000:023:011) (Box 32)
    - Logged Area, Yaak Vicinity, Montana, February 1999, (L2000:023:012) (Box 32)
    - Robyn King and Jimmy Martin, Yaak, Montana, February 1999, (L2000:023:013) (Box 32)
    - Summer Solstice Evening Sky over Karuzas' Home, Yaak Valley, Montana, 1999, (L2000:023:017) (Box 32)
    - Roadless Area, Yaak Valley, Montana, February 1999, (L2000:023:001a-b); (2 prints) (Box 38)
    - Top of Hensley Hill, Yaak, Montana, June 1999 (2 prints), (L2000:023:003 a-b); (2 prints) (Box 38)
  - Lauren Greenfield (United States, b. 1966)
    Twenty-six 13x20 and 16x20" Cibachrome prints of individuals in the San Francisco neighborhood of Bayview/Hunter's Point. Many of the young people in these portraits are Youthline "listeners," who support a social network and gateway to youth services for teens in the area.
    - Karen Cortez (on right), age 17, 1999, (L2000:047:014) (Box 29)
      She does a pop dance routine outside her apartment with her "sister" Jessica Ramos and her friend Michelle Lawrence as her grandmother and aunt watch them from the window. Karen was raised by her grandmother (who speaks no English) and her father, after her mother abandoned her as a child to return to her native El Salvador.
    - Bayview/Hunter's Point Apartment, 1999, (L2000:047:017) (Box 29)
      There is a constant activity of drug transactions outside the window of Ayana and Asante's impeccably clean apartment in Bayview-Hunters Point. Ayana and her friend joke about the boys who sell "copa," the name of a hair gel product the girls use as a code word for crack. Bay View is the poorest neighborhood in San Francisco and Mamie Matthews has always been very active in the community. The drug dealers know Mamie and her family and, out of respect, do not loiter directly in front of her building.
    - Youthline listener Asante Matthews, age 21, 1999, (L2000:047:019) (Box 29)
      She does her mother's hair in their apartment in Bayview-Hunters Point as the family prepares for church on Sunday. Asante's mother Mamie has seven children of her own and four foster children. Ayana and Asante help their mother care for the children but will be leaving for college in Atlanta in the fall. They are the first in their large family to attend a four-year college. Enter scope/content note.
    - Violeta Perez, 21, and her sister Massiel Perez, 15, at The Limited in the Stonestown Galleria shopping mall, shopping for clothes for her cousin's quinceañera, 1999, (L2000:047:020) (Box 29)
    - Molly Katzman, 17, tries on clothes in the Express dressing room at the mall in the suburb of Corte Madera, 1999, (L2000:047:021) (Box 29)
    - Josh Farr, age 19, sits with his mother Rosa Robinson at the San Francisco airport before leaving for a trip to Houston that precedes his going away to college, 1999, (L2000:047:022) (Box 29)
      Rosa says she always cries when Josh leaves. He is an only child and she a single mother so they both await with trepidation his imminent departure for the University of Wisconsin where he has received a full scholarship and will be the only African American student in his program.
    - Listener Evelyn Lock, age 17, plays dominoes during a slow period on shift at Youthline, 1999, (L2000:047:024) (Box 29)
    - Youthline listener Karen Cortez, 17, on her graduation day from Balboa High School, 1999, (L2000:047:002) (Box 34)
      She has been admitted to the University of California at Santa Barbara on a scholarship and will be the first person in her family to atten a four-year college.
    - Youthline listener Nina Rudnick, age 17, in her bedroom in Berkeley, gets paged by her boyfriend, 1999, (L2000:047:006) (Box 34)
    - Listener Suemyra Shah, age 17, a political activist and University of California at Berkeley student, protests cuts in the Ethnic Studies department at Santa Clara University, 1999, (L2000:047:007) (Box 34)
      She was one of the leaders of the successful U.C. Berkeley protests on the same issue for which students had hunger strikes and mounted tent cities.
    - Youthline listeners pose for a group portrait at Expressly Portraits at the Stonestown Galleria shopping mall, 1999, (L2000:047:010) (Box 34)
      Many listeners socialize together and two of them who are leaving for college wanted a picture of their Youthline friends to bring with them.
    - Listener Violeta Perez, age 19, fills out a questionnaire during a call, 1999, (L2000:047:015) (Box 34)
      Every caller remains anonymous but gets asked a standard set of informational questions during the course of their call.
    - Youthline listener Violeta Perez, age 19, talks on her cell phone during a shopping spree at the Stonestown Galleria shopping mall, 1999, (L2000:047:016) (Box 34)
    - Listener Ruth Barajas, age 18, in a meeting at Youthline, 1999, (L2000:047:004) (Box 34, Box 35)
    - Karen Cortez, age 17, gets her brow pierced at Body Manipulations, 1999, (L2000:047:008) (Box 34)
      She goes to the piercing studio planning on a tongue-pierce but after being told that her tongue is the wrong shape, ends up getting a brow pierce like her sister instead. Enter scope/content note.
    - Ruth Barajas, age 18, talks to her boyfriend during her shift at Youthline, 1999, (L2000:047:011) (Box 34)
      The Youthline listeners say that many of the support calls they get are about relationships.
    - Youthline listener Ed King, age 21, has a barbecue with his close friend in a San Francisco suburb. They throw lighter fluid on the barbecue to raise the flames higher, 1999, (L2000:047:013) (Box 34)
    - Listeners Ayana and Asante Matthews (on left), age 21, in their "street soldiers academic preparation class for girls and women" at the Omega Boys and Girls Club, 1999, (L2000:047:025) (Box 34)
      They listen as girls describe times in their life during which they were scared. Ayana describes a time when she and Asante were attacked in their car at a stoplight. One girl describes having a baby as a teenager. Another girl is afraid of kids at school with guns. Another reveals her fear that there is a contract on her life.Enter scope/content note.
    - William Walker, age 19, eats Cheetos during a Youthline meeting during which listeners prepare an outreach presentation, 1999, (L2000:047:001) (Box 36)
    - Nina Rudnick's backpack, 1999, (L2000:047:003) (Box 36)
    - Karen Cortez holds her 14-year old cousin's new baby in the apartment she shares with her father, brother and grandmother on her 18th birthday. Her other cousin, Jessica Ramos, talks on the phone to her boyfriend, 1999, (L2000:047:005) (Box 36)
    - Listener Aya Cash, age 17, takes a support call from an anonymous youth during her shift at Youthline, 1999, (L2000:047:009) (Box 36)
    - Violeta Perez, age 21, hugs her boyfriend who has been confined to a wheelchair since he was shot in an incident of gang violence, 1999, (L2000:047:012) (Box 36)
    - Youthline listener Ruth Barajas, age 18, role-plays a "support" telephone call with a student during a community outreach event in Bayview-Hunters Point, a poor neighborhood in San Francisco, 1999, (L2000:047:018) (Box 36)
    - Youthline listener Aya Cash, age 17, in her basement room in the house she shares with her mother, a poet, 1999, (L2000:047:023) (Box 36)
      Aya, an aspiring actress, gets ready for school, looking for books and other necessities under piles of clothes and teenage artifacts.
    - Ayana Matthews, 17, talks to her sister on the phone outside their apartment in Bayview-Hunters Point, 1999, (L2000:047:026) (Box 36)
  - Joan Liftin (United States, b. 1935)
    Eighteen 16x20" black-and-white gelatin silver prints of African Americans and Haitian Americans and their communities in Delray Beach, Florida. They are involved with several volunteer organizations to provide community policing, assist immigrants, and promote cultural understanding.
    - Swinton Avenue, Delray, Florida, Haitian Quarter, 1999, (L2000:035:001) (Box 27)
    - Interior, Haitian American home, 1999, (L2000:035:002) (Box 27)
    - The Beach at Night, 1999, (L2000:035:003) (Box 27)
    - Daughter of one of the dancers rehearsing for Haitian Flag Day ceremonies, 1999, (L2000:035:004) (Box 27)
    - Fourth of July picnic, 1999, (L2000:035:005) (Box 27)
    - Backyard, Sunday morning, 1999, (L2000:035:006) (Box 27)
    - Robert Augustin and his baby sister, 1999, (L2000:035:007) (Box 27)
    - Near Delray Beach, Florida, 1999, (L2000:035:008) (Box 27)
    - Fremiaud Basse holds photo of his fiancé, who drowned along with forty other Haitians when their boat capsized twelve miles off Florida shore, near Delray, 1999, (L2000:035:009) (Box 27)
    - Fourth of July church picnic, near Delray Beach, Florida, 1999, (L2000:035:010) (Box 27)
    - Delray Beach, Florida, 1999, (L2000:035:011) (Box 27)
    - Haitian patrol volunteer Wilner Athouriste, 1999, (L2000:035:012) (Box 27)
    - MAD DADS, an antidrug and volunteer street-patrol group, Delray, 1999, (L2000:035:013) (Box 27)
    - Restaurant Chez Zette, 1999, (L2000:035:014) (Box 27)
    - Good Friday Procession; a particularly mournful event this year, coming soon after the drowning of forty Haitians on boats making for Delray, 1999, (L2000:035:015) (Box 27)
    - Member of the storefront congregation of Adner Elmon, 1999, (L2000:035:016) (Box 27)
    - Haitian apartment, Delray, 1999, (L2000:035:017) (Box 27)
    - Palm Beach County Stockade Correctional Facility, 1999, (L2000:035:018) (Box 27)
  - Reagan Louie (United States, b. 1951)
    Sixteen 20x24 and 30x38 chromogenic prints of individuals in north Philadelphia involved with the Village of Arts and Humanities, a community effort focused on reclaiming declining neighborhoods through educational programs, the arts, and community-based social services.
    - Casey Ayers (with blindfold) and Raheem Wilson play pin-the-tail-on-the-donkey during a baby shower given for a teen mom at the Village, 1999, (L2000:032:003) (Box 32)
    - An after-school art class, 1999, (L2000:032:007) (Box 32)
    - Mosaic sculpture in Ile Ife Park, by Joseph "Jo Jo" Williams and James "Big Man" Maxton, 1999, (L2000:032:008) (Box 32)
    - Angel Alley murals designed by Lily Yeh: "Angel Alley" (left) mosaic created by James "Big Man" Maxton and "Angel Eyes" (right) mosaic created by Carolyn Overholt and Brother Mohammed, 1999, (L2000:032:009) (Box 32)
    - Bahia Beasley and a woman tie ribbons on newly planted trees, 1999, (L2000:032:011) (Box 32)
    - Village staff members Sally Hammerman and Andres Chamorro performing with puppets on Earth Day, 1999, (L2000:032:012) (Box 32)
    - Inlaid tile and stone floor of Meditation Park, 1999, (L2000:032:001) (Box 40)
    - James "Big Man" Maxton at home, 1999, (L2000:032:002) (Box 40)
    - Long View of the Village's Tree Farm, 1999, (L2000:032:004) (Box 40)
    - Casey Ayers and Ora Eldridge at a teen group meeting, 1999, (L2000:032:005) (Box 40)
    - Boy playing hide-and-seek in Ile Ife Park, 1999, (L2000:032:006) (Box 40)
    - Kitchen and entertainment center in a house being rehabilitated by the Village, 1999, (L2000:032:010) (Box 40)
    - Neighborhood resident Davore Henderson playing guitar, 1999, (L2000:032:013) (Box 40)
    - Lily Yeh works with a neighborhood boy in Fairhill Park, Cumberland and Tenth, 1999, (L2000:032:014) (Box 45)
    - "Magical Garden" tile mural designed by Lily Yeh, Warnock Street, 1999, (L2000:032:015) (Box 45)
    - Girls playing on Germantown Avenue, 1999, (L2000:032:016) (Box 45)
  - Danny Lyon (United States, b. 1942), Building on the Border
    Twenty 11x14 and 16x20" Cibachrome and black-and-white gelatin silver prints of Texan farmworkers and their communities near the Mexican border. Founded by the Farmworker's Union in 1991 to provide decent and affordable housing for farmworkers and their families, Proyecto Azteca benefits these community members, who also volunteer for building projects.
    - The Valley. Elissa Villareal, Benito Castillo and Heidy Rios Aleman at the All Valley Flea Market dance, 1999, (L2000:009:001) (Box 29)
    - A historic marker for the spot "where American blood was shed on American soil," along with murals from Mission, and the Farm Workers Union hall in Pharr, 1999, (L2000:009:002) (Box 29)
      In 1847 Congressman Abraham Lincoln declared that "the spot" was not, nor never had been part of Texas or the United States, and therefore could not justify an invasion of Mexico. This unpopular sentiment ruined his political career for the next decade.
    - A farm worker, Rolando Garcia, sings into an onion, with the bus schedule out of McAllen, 1999, (L2000:009:003) (Box 40)
    - Homes and interiors at Colonia Jessups with Lauro Pérez preparing lunch at the Proyecto Azteca site, 1999, (L2000:009:004) (Box 40)
    - María Lopez at home in a colonia near Alamo, Texas, 1999, (L2000:033:001) (Box 41)
    - At the All Valley Flea Market Dance, 1999, (L2000:033:003) (Box 41)
    - Martha Rángel harvesting onions near Mercedes. Ms. Rángel carries her immigration papers in her back pocket in case she has to show them to INS workers, 1999, (L2000:033:004) (Box 41)
    - Aristeo Orta, a construction worker at Proyecto Azteca, 1999, (L2000:033:002) (Box 41)
    - Noe Galindo, Colonia Jessups, near Monte Alto, 1999, (L2000:033:005) (Box 41)
    - Farm worker in a field near Monte Alto, 1999, (L2000:033:006) (Box 41)
    - The dance hall, All Valley Flea Market, 1999, (L2000:033:007) (Box 41)
    - Epifanio Morales at Proyecto Azteca, 1999, (L2000:033:008) (Box 41)
    - Taco stand, downtown McAllen, 1999, (L2000:033:009) (Box 28)
    - Roberto Rodríguez's family near Edinburg, 1999, (L2000:033:010) (Box 27)
    - Pay phone, San Juan, Texas, 1999, (L2000:033:011) (Box 27)
    - Family at the flea market, Pharr, Texas, 1999, (L2000:033:012) (Box 27)
    - Farm worker, a regular at the All Valley Flea Market dance, cutting cabbage, 1999, (L2000:033:013) (Box 27)
    - At the All Valley Flea Market Dance, 1999, (L2000:033:014) (Box 27)
    - Farmers clear an onion field near Monte Alto, 1999, (L2000:033:015) (Box 27)
    - Route 281, the Military Highway, 1999, (L2000:033:016) (Box 27)
      The horizon shows the Rio Grande River, established as the border with Mexico after the War of 1848.
  - Sylvia Plachy (United States, b. 1943, Hungary)
    Fourteen 16x20 and 20x24" gelatin silver prints documenting the training and work of community doulas and midwives in Ithaca, N.Y., and the families who benefit from their support before, during, and after childbirth.
    - Jacqueline Shepard and another student in their doula class train for labor support through role-playing, 1999, L2000:034:001 (Box 39)
    - Doula Jacqueline Shepard caring for Sunshin Gordon, 1999, (L2000:034:002) (Box 39)
    - Jacqueline Shepard in her brother's backyard holds up portraits of her role models, her mother and her sister, 1999, (L2000:034:003) (Box 39)
    - Lise Golub, at a postpartum visit, delights in Olivia Gordon, a baby whose birth she recently attended as a doula mentor, 1999, (L2000:034:004) (Box 39)
    - Robert Gordon holds his new baby, Olivia, before she is taken to the nursery, 1999, (L2000:034:005) (Box 39)
    - Olivia studies her father, Robert Gordon, minutes after being born, 1999, (L2000:034:006) (Box 39)
    - Sunshin, Robert and Olivia Gordon pose for their first formal family portrait, 1999, (L2000:034:007) (Box 39)
    - Jane Arnold, midwife, attends Sunshin and Robert Gordon hours before the birth of their first child, 1999, (L2000:034:008) (Box 39)
    - Robert Gordon holds Sunshin as first-time doula Jacqueline Shepard adds support, 1999, (L2000:034:009) (Box 39)
    - Sunshin Gordon resting between contractions, 1999, (L2000:034:010) (Box 39)
    - Robert attending to Sunshin Gordon during a wave of pain, 1999, (L2000:034:011) (Box 39)
    - Sunshin Gordon is comforted by the hands of midwife Jane Arnold and doula Jacqueline Shepard, 1999, (L2000:034:012) (Box 39)
    - Robert and Sunshin Gordon hold their new firstborn, Olivia, 1999, (L2000:034:013) (Box 33)
    - Jane Arnold, midwife, hands Sunshin and Robert Gordon their new baby, Olivia, 1999, (L2000:034:014) (Box 33)
  - Eli Reed (United States, b. 1946)
    Eighteen 16x20" framed gelatin silver prints of community volunteers and their friends in Eau Claire, South Carolina.
    - Leroy Moss, a community worker and activist who is blind, at the recreational center that is named in his honor, 1999, (L2000:031:001) (Box 31)
    - Reverend Wiley Cooper teaching children about the many portrayals of Jesus, 1999, (L2000:031:002) (Box 31)
    - Scott Trent Jr., former president of the Eau Claire Community Council, looking at graffiti on the Norfolk-Southern railroad trestle on North Main Street, 1999, (L2000:031:003) (Box 31)
    - Henry Hopkins, local organizer and executive director of the Eau Claire Community council, at a meeting on the prevention of violence, 1999, (L2000:031:004) (Box 31)
    - An Eau Claire street at dusk, 1999, (L2000:031:005) (Box 31)
    - Rhett Anders, current Eau Claire Community Council president and real estate agent, in front of a historic local property, 1999, (L2000:031:006) (Box 31)
    - Fran Potter, a member of the zoning board and former president of the Eau Claire Community Council, (L2000:031:007) (Box 31)
    - Reverend Wylie Cooper of Shalom and volunteers help rehabilitate the home of an elderly resident, 1999, (L2000:031:008) (Box 31)
    - Lee Bolton and a Shalom member do yard work as part of their housing rehabilitation effort with the Eau Claire Community of Shalom, 1999, (L2000:031:009) (Box 31)
    - Church members at Wesley United Methodist Church prior to a baptism service, 1999, (L2000:031:010) (Box 31)
    - Rotary Club Meeting, 1999, (L2000:031:011) (Box 31)
    - Toliver's Mane Event barbershop, 1999, (L2000:031:012) (Box 31)
    - Men's Breakfast Group leaving College Place United Methodist Church, where they have met for over fifty years, 1999, (L2000:031:013) (Box 31)
    - A local senior artist hands a bouquet she made to a visitor, 1999, (L2000:031:014) (Box 31)
    - The South Carolina National Guard participates in a local parade in an Eau Claire neighborhood, 1999, (L2000:031:015) (Box 31)
    - Playing baseball at a trailer park on Fairfield Road, 1999, (L2000:031:016) (Box 31)
    - Columbia chief of police Charles Austin, Sr. baptizes Brandon Hawkins at Central Baptist Church, 1999, (L2000:031:017) (Box 31)
    - Scott Trent Jr. has lived in the same house in Eau Claire for nineteen years, 1999, (L2000:031:018) (Box 31)